<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<list>
  <PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
    <short_name>ST</short_name>
    <long_name>strength</long_name>
    <description>
      You know, muscle. Boom! Boom! Fiah Powah. Note that physical size and
      fitness play a role in many "strength" related tasks; in particular, ST
      is "short term power", for any long term activity Fitness will have to be
      taken into account.
    </description>
  </PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
  <PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
    <short_name>FT</short_name>
    <long_name>fitness</long_name>
    <description>
      Fitness is usually called Constitution, Health, or Endurance. I made a
      distinction here because I wanted to emphasis the difference between
      "strong" (high ST) and "athletic" (high FT). Fitness, along with
      Willpower determines your resistance to various physical challenges. Raw
      size also plays a role in how much "damage" you can absorb.
    </description>
  </PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
  <PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
    <short_name>CO</short_name>
    <long_name>coordination</long_name>
    <description>
      Coordination is the primary stat for physical skills, it represents "slow
      and deliberate" actions and as such is analogous to FT as RF is to
      strength.
    </description>
  </PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
  <PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
    <short_name>RX</short_name>
    <long_name>reflexes</long_name>
    <description>
      Reflexes determine a characters "fast" reaction speed, it affects
      physical skills and tasks where speed is of the essence.
    </description>
  </PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
  <PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
    <short_name>PE</short_name>
    <long_name>perception</long_name>
    <description>
      Perception, of course, has a physical as well as mental component. The
      stat here represents not just observing your surroundings, but making
      correct conclusions base on them. It might also be termed "instinctual
      intelligence", as compared to Reason.
    </description>
  </PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
  <PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
    <short_name>RE</short_name>
    <long_name>reason</long_name>
    <description>
      Reason is the higher order brain stat. It is the primary governing stat
      of "book learning" skills; such that you might learn at school. It also
      helps in puzzle solving and designing or utilizing novel tools or
      gadgets.
    </description>
  </PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
  <PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
    <short_name>CH</short_name>
    <long_name>charisma</long_name>
    <description>
      Charisma is the how you win friends and influence people. It is the
      primary determinant for raw reaction rolls and most social and leadership
      skills. It is not how good looking you are (there are traits for that),
      but can substitute in some instances.
    </description>
  </PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
  <PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
    <short_name>WL</short_name>
    <long_name>willpower</long_name>
    <description>
      Willpower is in someways the mental analogy of Fitness. It plays a strong
      role in survival of some types of hazards as well as determining, in
      part, the characters' learning rate. A high WL low FT character is going
      to get himself in a lot of trouble, because he will push his body to the
      breaking point and past it.
    </description>
  </PrimaryCharacterStatistic>
</list>